●IDISK 최강 영화클럽●
●씨네무비 클럽●
제작 :
파라마운틴 영화사
기획 :
라파엘라 드 로렌티스, 존 애브넷
감독 :
케리 콘랜
기네스 펠트로 (폴리 퍼킨스 役)
주드 로 스카이 (스카이 캡틴 役)
안젤리나 졸리 (프랭키 쿡 役)
월드 오브 투모로우
힌덴부르크 III
모두 주의하시기 바랍니다
착륙 절차가 준비 중입니다
Attention. Please prepare
for docking procedure.
착륙 준비
이보게나...
착륙하는 즉시 이 소포를
전달 좀 해주겠나?
네, 바가스 박사님
월터 제닝스 박사에게
전해주게
네, 박사님,
바로 해드리죠
"제닝스 박사,
난 미행당하고 있소"
"이 물건을 잘 지키시오"
-바가스-
"힌덴부르크 III호, 뉴욕 상공
제국에 정박중"
"과학자 실종, 경찰 수색중"
-폴리 퍼킨스 기자-
폴리 퍼킨스
미스 퍼킨스,
소포가 배달됐습니다
There's a package for you,
Miss Perkins.
이름은 밝히지 않았습니다
They didn't leave a name.
- 중요하다고 하더군요
- 고마워요
- Said it was important.
- Thank you.
"다음 차례가 누군지 압니다"
"오늘 6시에 만납시다
꼭 혼자 나오시오!"
"라디오 시티 극장"
-입장권-
이번 건은 영 꺼림찍해
너무 깊숙힌 들어가지마!
I don't like this business
you're getting yourself into.
패일리, 괜찮을거예요
제가 얼마나 신중한지 알잖아요
I'll be just fine, Mr. Paley.
You know what a careful girl I am.
내가 무슨 말을 하든
귀 담아 듣질 않는군
I move my mouth, words come out,
you don't hear.
극장에 늦었어요
- I'm late for a movie.
- I don't like it when you smile at me.
내게 그런 미소 짓는것두
마음에 안 드는군
제 미소가 마음에
안든다구요?
You don't like my smile?
그 미소 뒤에 감춰진 게
싫다는 거야
I don't like what's behind it.
폴리, 잘 들어
과학자 6명이 실종됐어
Listen, Polly, six scientists are missing,
probably dead.
십중팔구는
죽었겠지만 말야
누군진 몰라도
이건 장난이 아니야
Somebody out there means business.
I don't want you in the middle of it.
폴리가 끼어드는게 싫어
그냥 영화보러
가는 거라구요, 패일리
It's only a movie, Mr. Paley.
팝콘 갖다 드릴께요
I'll bring you some popcorn.
"토토, 느낄수가 있어
우린 지금 캔사스에 있는게 아냐"
Toto, I have a feeling
we're not in Kansas anymore.
"우린 무지개너머에
있는게 틀림없어"
We must be over the rainbow.
이걸 보낸게
당신 맞나요?
You sent me this?
당신은 누구죠?
Who are you?
도대체 이게 다 뭐죠
미스터...?
- What's this all about, Mr...?
- Doctor.
박사요
월터 제닝스 박사,
난 화학분야가 전공이죠
Dr. Walter Jennings.
I'm a research chemist.
핵산(核酸) 추출분야의
전문가요
I specialize in nucleic-acid emissions.
효소와 분자의 결합과정에서
그 둘 사이에 가변성의...
The bonding enzymes
in proteus molecules which...
실종된 과학자들, 다음 차례가
누군지 안다고 하셨죠?
The missing scientists.
You said you knew who was next.
그래요, 내가...
Yes, l...
기사 마감이 얼마 남질
않아서요, 박사님
I have a deadline to meet, doctor.
내가 7명의 과학자중
마지막이오
I was one of seven scientists
chosen to serve in a secret facility
우리들은 비밀스런
단체에서 일을 했소
stationed outside of Berlin
before the start of the First World War.
세계 1차 대전 이전, 베를린
외곽의 극비 시설이었소
단지 통일 전선이라고만 알려진
조직에서 "유닛 11"을 진행했소
It was known only as Einheit Elf,
"Unit 11."
우린 그 일에 관해서는
절대 누설하지 않기로 했죠
We agreed never to discuss
what went on behind those doors.
우리가 거기서
만들었던건 아주...
The things we were made
to do there...
끔찍한 것이었소
Terrible things.
- 당신, 여기 오지 말았어야 했소
- "우리도 캔사스가 아닌 줄 알아요"
- I shouldn't have come.
- Now I know we're not in Kansas.
"당신은 좋은 마녀예요, 아님 나쁜 마녀예요?"
Are you a good witch
or a bad witch?
박사님, 다음 차례가
누군지 안다고 하셨잖아요
Doctor, you said you knew
who was next.
그래요
Yes.
당신, 모르겠소?
Don't you see?
- 남은 사람은 딱 한명이니까요
- 누구죠? 그게 누구죠, 박사님?
- There is only one left.
- Who? Who is it, doctor?
나요
Me.
그들이 날 잡으러 올거요
He's coming for me.
누구요? 누가 온다는 거죠?
Who? Who's coming?
토튼코프
Totenkopf.
그가 토튼코프요
It's Totenkopf.
저기 봐!
There!
모든 시민에게 알립니다
모두 주목해 주십시오
All citizens, attention.
즉시 뉴욕시에서
대피해 주시기 바랍니다
New York City
must be evacuated at once.
질서있게 동쪽 강변로를
이용해 이동하십시오
Proceed in an orderly manner
to the East River Drive.
모든 경찰 및 소방대원들은
담당구역에서 벗어나시오
All members of the police and fire
department on leave or off duty
지금 즉시 관할 지구대나
중앙본부에 보고하기 바랍니다
shall report immediately to their
precincts or company command.
긴급 상황입니다
This is urgent.
- 패일리 편집장입니다
- 패일리, 저예요, 폴리
- Editor Paley.
- Mr. Paley, it's me, Polly.
어떻게 된거야?
도심에서 모두 대피하라는데
What's going on? They're calling
for midtown to evacuate.
잘들어요, 패일리
시간이 없어요
Listen, Mr. Paley,
I don't have much time.
필요한 정보가 있는데
조사 좀 해줘요
I need you to dig up anything you can
on a Dr. Walter Jennings
윌터 제닝스 박사와
토튼코프라고 불리는
인물이에요
and someone named Totenkopf.
An address, a phone number,
anything you can find. It's important.
주소라든가, 전화번호,
뭐든간에 찾아줘요, 중요해요
토튼코프, 그게 누구지?
Totenkopf. Who is he?
실종된 과학자들과
관계가 있는 사람같아요
He may have something to do
with the missing scientists.
빨리 알아봐
Quick as you can.
폴리, 내 말 잘들어
빨리 그곳에서 피해
Polly, listen to me.
I want you to get out of there.
거길 빨리 떠나라구,
전화 끊고, 노트도 덮고
I want you to put the phone down,
close your notepad
그 지옥에서 빨리 나와
and get the hell out of there.
잠깐만요
Wait a minute.
지금 뭔가가 팰리세이즈
상공으로 다가오고 있어요
I can see something now coming
into sight above the Palisades.
아베뉴 6번가가의
교차로를 지나고 있어요
They're crossing Sixth Avenue.
아베뉴 5번가
Fifth Avenue.
100야드... 그들과
100야드 정도 떨어져 있어요
They're a hundred...
They're a hundred yards away.
폴리! 폴리!
Polly. Polly!
이런 세상에..
Oh, my God.
폴리!
Polly!
멈춰! 돌아와요!
Stop! Come back!
발사!
Fire!
여기서 피해!
Get out of here!
경계선을 돌파당했습니다
병력지원을 요청합니다
They've broken through the perimeter.
Send reinforcements.
움직일 수 있는 모든 병력을
보내주기 바랍니다
Send everything you've got!
비상 교신 '90206'
Emergency protocol 90206. Calling
Sky Captain. Come in, Sky Captain.
스카이 캡틴, 응답하라
스카이 캡틴, 들리는가?
반복한다, 스카이 캡틴,
응답하라
Repeat. Calling Sky Captain.
Come in, Sky Captain.
스카이 캡틴, 나와라
여기는 비상 교신 '90206'
This is an emergency
protocol, 90206.
스카이 캡틴, 응답하라
스카이 캡틴, 들리는가?
Calling Sky Captain.
Sky Captain, do you read?
스카이 캡틴, 응답하라
스카이 캡틴, 나와라
Calling Sky Captain.
Come in, Sky Captain.
여기는
비상 교신 '90206'
This is an emergency
protocol, 90206.
스카이 캡틴, 응답하라
스카이 캡틴, 들리는가?
Calling Sky Captain.
Sky Captain, do you read?
반복한다, 스카이 캡틴,
응답하라
Repeat. Calling Sky Captain.
Come in, Sky Captain.
스카이 캡틴, 나와라
여기는 스카이 캡틴,
그 곳으로 가는 중이다
This is Sky Captain. I'm on my way.
폴리
Polly.
조
Joe.
무자비한 공격부대의
지속적인 공격으로 인해
Further details of the attack
continue to pour in.
"기계로 만든 괴물들
전력시설 파괴하다"
시내 중심부에서 파괴되면서
대부분의 통신이 두절되고
The central portion of the city is
blacked out from radio communication
전력 배송선의 손상으로 인해
대부분의 전력이 차단되었습니다
due to damaged power lines
and electrical failure.
영국, 프랑스, 독일의
외신 내용에 의하면
Cables received from English, French
and German news agencies
시내에만 국한된 공격이
아님이 확인되었습니다
now confirm the attack
was not limited to the city.
영국 BBC의 보도에 의하면
뉴렌베르그의 제철 공장이
The BBC is reporting
that a steel mill in Nuremberg
사실상 파괴됐다고 합니다
was virtually excavated
목격자들의 말에 의하면
기계들의 폭풍같았다고 합니다
by what witnesses describe
as a mechanized tornado.
파리와 마드리드 외신은
이상한 소리를 내는 기계들이
News agencies in Paris and Madrid
speak of strange burrowing machines
땅속에서 치솟아 올라와
rising from the ground,
비축된 원유와 석탄을
강탈해갔다고 전합니다
robbing entire communities
of their coal and oil reserves.
군용 자원의 상당량이
사라짐에 따라
Meanwhile, with military resources
stretched thin across the globe,
전 세계 지도자들은
캡틴 스카이와
world leaders
must once again call upon
그의 용병부대를 고용하여
이 전대미문의 사태에 대한
the elite mercenary forces
of Sky Captain and his army-for-hire
의문을 조사하기로
결정했습니다
to uncover the meaning
of these mysterious events.
덱스는 어딨지?
Where's Dex?
와우
Shazam.
덩치가 크다고 하지 않았나요?
내가 가져도 돼요?
I thought you said this thing was big.
Can I have it?
저게 어디서 온건지 알아낸다면
크리스마스 선물로 하나 주지
You find out where it came from,
and I'll buy you one for Christmas.
보여줄게 있어요
Oh, I need to show you something.
첫번째 기계가 나타나기 전에
신호를 녹음했어요
I recorded this signal just before
the first machine appeared.
다시 들어보기 전까지는
중요하게 생각하지 않았는데
I didn't think anything of it
until I played it back.
- 모스 부호?
- 저도 처음엔 그런줄 알았는데
- Morse code?
- See, that's what I thought at first,
그런데 체계가
훨씬 더 복잡해요
but the syntax
is more complex than that.
저주파 대역 속에
부반송파가 숨겨져 있어요
There's a sub-carrier hidden
in the lower frequency.
아마 이걸로 기계들을
조종하는것 같아요
I think it's being used
to control them.
다시 나타난다면
추적 할 수 있겠지?
If it shows up again,
could you track it?
해볼께요
I can try, yeah.
- 잘했어, 덱스
- 고마워요
- Good boy, Dex.
- Thanks.
우선 저것 부터
조사해 봐야겠군
In the meantime,
see what you can do with that thing.
어떻게 작동시키는 알아봐
Find out what makes it tick.
- 괜찮겠지?
- 네, 괜찮아요
- You don't mind, do you?
- I don't mind.
어디서 온건지 알아봐, 덱스
누가 보낸건지도
I wanna know where it comes from,
Dex. Who sent it here.
이동 좌표는
'69 SW' 에서 '49 E'로
Switch to map coordinate
69 SW by 49 E.
복통이야?
Tummy ache?
조, 잘 지냈어?
How you been, Joe?
- 나 보고 싶었어?
- 나가
- Miss me?
- Get out.
난 상당히 반가운데
Well, it's nice to see you too.
덱스가 그러던데
당신 기분이 지금 별로라고
Dex said you might be in a mood.
덱스가?
Dex?
들어와!
Get in here!
조, 벌써 3년이나 지났어
아직도 화가 안 풀렸어?
It's been three years, Joe.
You're not still mad at me, are you?
왜 싸웠는지조차
기억이 안 나는데
Can't even remember
what we were fighting about.
내 비행기를 망가뜨렸잖아
You sabotaged my plane.
그랬었지
Right.
너 때문에 만주 노동수용소에
6개월이나 갇혀 있었어
I spent six months in a Manchurian
slave camp because of you.
- 하마트면 손가락 잘릴뻔 했어
- 조
- They were gonna cut off my fingers.
- Joe,
다시한번 말하지만
for the last time, I didn't sabotage
your damn airplane.
난 절대로 네 잘나빠진
비행기를 파괴하지 않았어
넌 가운을 입고 있는
'토조 히데키'의
All so you could get a photograph
of Tojo Hideki
사진을 찍을 기회를
엿보고 있었지, 기억나?
in his bathrobe, remember?
당신도 알다시피
그런 생각도 할 수 있지
You know, I'm starting to think
당신이 그 소동을 혼자
꾸며냈다는 생각도 드는군
that you've invented
this whole sabotage nonsense
몰래 숨겨논 어린 년과
놀아났다는 걸 감추려고
to cover the fact that
you were running around on me
우리가 난징에 있는 내내
내 주위를 맴돈거 다 알아
with your little mystery girl
the whole time we were in Nanjing.
절대 그런 일 없었어
다 네 상상이야
Never happened.
All in your imagination.
그 여자 누구였어, 조?
Who was she, Joe?
- 이름이 뭐였지?
- 그만 해
- What was her name?
- That's enough.
어떻게 할건데?
What are you gonna do?
총이라도 쏘게?
Shoot me?
오, 이런,
아직 화해중이군
Oh, great. We all made up.
반가웠어, 폴리
It's been a pleasure, Polly.
10년 후에나 다시 만나지
퍼킨스양을 배웅해 주게, 덱스
Let's do it again in ten years.
Escort Miss Perkins off the base, Dex.
저항하면 쏴버려
If she resists, shoot her.
- 폴리, 안녕
- 덱스, 안녕
- Hi, Polly.
- Hi, Dex.
- 저, 난...
- 알아, 괜찮아
- I gotta...
- It's okay, hon, I know.
좋아
Okay.
어차피 이런 것엔 관심도
없을테니, 뭐 아무렴 어때
It's just as well. I guess you wouldn't
have been interested in this, anyway.
- 그거 어디서 났어?
- 이거 말고도 더 있지
- Where did you get that?
- There's more where this came from.
아주 많이
Lots more.
- 더 자세히 말해 봐, 폴리
- 난 기사꺼릴 원해, 조
- I want that blueprint, Polly.
- I want this story, Joe.
당신이 나 좀 도와줘
And you're gonna help me get it.
아까 그걸 보여주면, 우릴
도울 수 있을지도 모르죠
Maybe we should show her, Cap.
Maybe she can help.
뭘 보여줘?
Show me what?
뭘 보여준다는거야?
세상에, 이게 뭐야?
My God. What is this?
어디서 온거야?
Where do they come from?
3년 전부터 나타나기
시작했죠, 외진 곳에서요
They started appearing three years ago
in remote areas.
지금까지는 그럭저럭
비밀로 부칠 수 있었죠
We managed to keep it a secret
until now.
예고없이 나타나서는
필요한 것만 챙긴 다음
They show up without warning,
they take what they need,
소리소문도 없이
사라졌죠
and then they disappear
without a trace.
3년이나 됐는데도 뭘
원하는지 못 알아냈어요
Three years and we still can't explain
what they want
누가 보낸건지도요
or who's sending them here.
오늘 어떤 과학자가
날 찾아왔었어
A man came to see me today,
a scientist.
겁에 질려서는 자기를
잡으러 올거라고 하길래
He was terrified.
Said someone was coming for him.
누굴 그렇게 무서워하냐고
물었더니 이름을 얘기했어
I asked him who he was so afraid of,
and he repeated one name:
토튼코프
Totenkopf.
말할 때 얼굴이
하얗게 질려있었어
He nearly went white
when he said it.
토튼코프? 그게 누구죠?
Totenkopf, who is he?
투명인간이라도 되나 봐
He's the invisible man.
모든 도서관에서 인명록을
두번씩이나 뒤지고
I've been through every library record
twice looking for anything.
파리에서 방콕까지 모든
정보원들에게 연락해봤지만
I've called every contact I have
from Paris to Bangkok.
알아낸 건 단지
이거 하나뿐이야
This is the only thing I could dig up.
베를린 외곽에서 과학자들과
비밀조직을 운영했었어
He ran some kind of secret
science unit outside of Berlin
제1차 세계 대전이
시작되기 전부터
before the start of World War I.
'유닛 11' 이라
불리는 조직이야
Something called Unit 11.
30년간 누구도 그 이름을
언급하지 않았어
It's been more than 30 years
since anyone has spoken his name.
오늘까지
Until today.
유닛의 상징으로 뭘
사용했는지 잘 봐
Note the insignia he used
for the unit.
이 기계들 위에 있는
표식하고 일치해
It matches the markings
on all of these machines.
그 과학자,
그는 지금 어딨어?
The scientist, where is he now?
우리 함께하는거지?
그렇지, 조?
We're in this together, right, Joe?
나한테 물어보기 전까진
어떤것도 신문에 나면 안돼
Nothing gets published until I say so.
You don't write a sentence
기사 한줄도, 사진 한장도
찍으면 안돼, 알겠지?
or take a photograph without
asking me first. Understood?
알았어
Understood.
왜?
What?
보고 싶었어
I missed you.
참, 오늘 내 목숨
구해줘서 고마웠어
Thanks for saving my life today,
by the way.
거기에 있던게 너였어?
Were you down there?
당신도 내가 보고 싶었군
기분 좋은데
You missed me too. How nice.
여기야, 여기가 바로
제닝스 박사의 실험실이야
This is it. This is Jennings' lab.
제닝스 박사님!
폴리 퍼킨스예요
Dr. Jennings? It's Polly Perkins.
제닝스 박사님!
Dr. Jennings!
잠겼어
It's locked.
저기 창문 봐
That window there.
저 창문으로
들어갈 수 있을거야
I may be able to get in
through that window
밧줄만 연결하면 될텐데
if I can attach a line...
열렸네
It's open.
한 발 늦었군
누가 먼저 왔었어
We're too late.
Someone beat us here.
좋아, 폴리...
All right, Polly...
...게임은 그만 해
도대체 무슨 일이 생긴거야?
...no more games.
What the hell is going on?
네가 설명해주길 바랬는데
I was hoping you could tell me.
제닝스 박사님!
Dr. Jennings!
그를 막아야 돼!
You must stop him!
가만히 있어요
Stay here.
멈춰!
Stop!
해치고 싶진 않아
I don't wanna hurt you.
- 퍼킨스양
- 여기 있어요, 박사님
- Miss Perkins.
- I'm here, doctor.
- 밖에가서 도움을 청할게요
- 약속해줘요
- I'm going to get you some help.
- You must promise.
만약 토튼코프가 그걸 찾으면
카운트다운이 시작될거요
If Totenkopf finds them,
the countdown will begin.
세상의 종말을 향한
- This world shall end.
- I don't understand, doctor. Find what?
무슨 말이에요? 박사님?
뭘 찾으면요?
약속해요...
Promise.
그는 죽었어
He's dead.
이걸 발견했어
I think I found something.
오늘 극장에서 함께 있을때
박사가 갖고 있던거야
Dr. Jennings had this with him
this morning at the theater.
- 기지로 돌아가야 돼
- 같이 갈거야
- I'd better get back to the base.
- I'm coming with you.
물론이겠지
Of course you are.
레이더에 뭔가가 잡혔는데
시속 500노트의 속도로
Reconnaissance picked up something
on radar traveling at over 500 knots
이곳으로 오고 있습니다
and coming straight for us.
- 도착하려면 얼마나 걸리지?
- 저기!
- How long before they reach us?
- There!
비행기 준비해, 출격한다
Get my plane ready. I'm going up.
- 뭐하는 거야?
- 같이 갈거야
- What are you doing?
- I'm coming with you.
바보 짓 마, 지난 번 같이
비행했다가 생긴 일 기억나?
Don't be stupid. Remember what
happened last time you flew with me?
- 약속했잖아
- 이건 게임이 아니야, 폴리
- We had a deal.
- This is not a game, Polly.
- 죽을지도 몰라
- 날 두고 혼자 갈 순 없어, 조
- People are gonna die.
- You are not leaving me, Joe.
아직 멀었어, 이건 내 기사야
그리고 약속했잖아!
Not this time. This is my story,
and we had a deal!
출발해, 출발하라구!
Go, go, go!
타
Get in.
저기 있다
There you are.
- 캡틴, 덱스입니다, 들립니까?
- 덱스, 난 지금 바빠
- Cap, this is Dex, do you read me?
- Hang on, Dex, I'm a little busy.
왜그래, 덱스
Come in, Dex.
무슨 일이 있어도
사격하지 마세요
Look, whatever you do, don't shoot!
- 알았어
- 벌써 쐈죠?
- Okay.
- You shot it, didn't you?
- 그래
- 잘들어요, 캡틴
- Yes.
- Listen, Cap,
한 기계에서 신호가
계속 나오고 있어요
the signal's coming
from one of those machines.
그 걸을 조각내면 안돼요
You gotta keep them
in one piece.
어떤거 말야, 덱스?
Which machine is it, Dex?
몰라요, 저것들 중
어느 한 대 일 겁니다
There's no way of telling.
It could be any one of them.
찾은것 같아, 덱스
I think I found it, Dex.
- 신호가 사라지고 있어요
- 시내로 향하고 있어
- Wait, Cap, I'm losing the signal.
- It's heading for the city.
놓치지 마세요
Don't let it get away. I need you
to bounce that signal back to me.
신호를 다시
제게 재전송 해줘야 돼요
놓치면 다시는
못 찾을지도 몰라요
If we lose it now,
we may never get it back.
뭐든지 알아내면
나한테 알려줘, 덱스
You let me know when
you've got something, Dex.
알겠습니다
I'll let you know. Out.
좋아, 수신되는 모든 신호를
전 주파수대에서 확인하고
All right, I want a full-spectrum sweep
of every incoming signal.
주파수 변화가 있으면
증폭해서 나한테 재전송 해
Amplify any variant frequency cycle
and route them to me.
발전기 때문에 돌아온거야
They've come back
for the generators.
도대체 어떤 놈이야?
Who is this guy?
- 당신, 괜찮아?
- 문제없어
- You okay?
- Great.
의자 밑에 보면 '위산 억제재'가
있을거야, 필요하면 먹어
There's a bottle of Milk of Magnesia
under the seat if you need it.
- 난 괜찮아
- 안 괜찮은것 같은데
- I'm fine.
- You don't look so good.
조심해!
Pull up!
- 조!
- 봤어
- Joe!
- I see it!
도망치고 있어
It's getting away.
- 캡틴, 신호를 놓쳤습니다
- 내가 찾을게, 덱스, 잘 잡아
- I lost the signal, Cap.
- I'll find him, Dex. Sit tight.
- 좌회전 해!
- 뒤에 앉아, 폴리
- Go left.
- Sit back, Polly.
브로드웨이를 통한
지름길이 있어
There's a shortcut down Broadway.
You can catch him on 42nd Street.
42번가에서
따라잡을 수 있어
여기 길은 손바닥처럼
훤히 알아, 좌측으로!
I know these streets like the back
of my hand. Go left!
이봐
Hey!
좋아, 좋아, 직진해!
Okay, okay, now go straight.
- 안돼, 안돼, 우회전!
- 언제?
- No, no, no, go right!
- When?
지났어
Back there.
다음 번에는 좀 더
일찍 알려줘
I could use a little more warning
next time.
좌회전!
Go left!
덱스, 뭘 좀 알아냈어?
Tell me you got something, Dex.
지금 사방에서
공격당하고 있어
We're getting clobbered up here.
여기도 만만치
않아요, 캡틴
It's no picnic down here either, Cap.
Hang in there, I've almost got it.
조금만 기다리세요
거의 다 됐어요
조!
Joe!
덱스, 더 이상
못 버티겠어
Dex! We can't hold them off
any longer!
- 거의 다 됐어요
- 지금 철수해야 돼!
- I'm almost there.
- We have to evacuate now!
먼저 가,
금방 따라갈께
Go ahead without me.
I'm right behind you.
- 멋져
- 약국쪽으로 좌회전
- Lovely.
- Okay, turn left at the drugstore.
- 다시 좌측
- 제 자리에서 빙빙 돌고 있잖아
- Left again.
- We're going around in circles.
그냥 내 말 믿어봐
죄회전 해
Will you just trust me? Go left!
- 막다른 골목이야
- 저게 왜 여기에 있지?
- It's a dead end.
- That's not supposed to be there.
막다른 골목이라구!
It's a dead end!
출구가 없어!
There's no way out!
오, 젠장
Oh, bugger.
조!
Joe!
- 저기 선두함이 있어
- 지름길이라구?
- There's the lead ship.
- Shortcut!
그래도 여기까지
안내했잖아?
I got us here, didn't I?
덱스!
- Dex. Dex!
- Thirty seconds, Cap, that's all I need.
- 댁스!
- 30초만 있으면 되요, 캡틴
- 30초?
- 대충 그 정도요
- Thirty seconds.
- Plus or minus.
바닷가로 유인해서
Listen, I'll try and take them out over
the water, buy us some time. Over.
시간을 벌어보도록
하겠다
아직도 따라오길
잘했다고 생각해?
Still glad you came?
조, 찾았어요!
Joe, I found it! Joe!
덱스, 어디 있어?
Dex, come in. Where is it?
덱스, 응답해
내 말 들려? 덱스?
Come in, Dex. Are you there? Dex?
덱스, 내 말 듣고있어?
Dex, do you read me?
덱스, 어디 있어?
Dex, are you there?
더 이상은 안되겠어
I can't outrun them much longer.
꽉 잡아
Hold on.
조, 뭐하는거야?
이러다가 추락하겠어!
Joe, what are you doing?
You're heading straight down!
- 당신, 우릴 죽일거야!
- 알아서 할테니, 진정해
- You're gonna kill us!
- I know what I'm doing. Just hold on.
너무 빨리 내려가고 있어
날 죽일 작정이야
We're going too fast.
We're not gonna make it.
조, 고도를 높여!
Joe, you have to pull up!
올라 가라구!
Pull up!
- 바닷속이잖아
- 덱스가 고안한거야
- We went underwater.
- Dex rigged it up.
만화책에서
아이디어를 얻었대
Got the idea from one
of his comic books.
당신, 다 알면서
여태까지 가만 있었어
You mean, you knew this
the whole time,
추락할 거라고 생각하게
놔뒀단 말이야?
and you let me think
we were gonna crash?
죽는 줄 알았잖아!
귀뜸을 해줬어야지!
I thought we were gonna die!
You should have said something!
폴리, 따라오겠다는건
네 생각이었어
Look, Polly, it was your idea
to tag along, not mine.
참을 수 없어도
내 잘못이 아니야
If you can't take it,
that's not my fault.
참을 수 있어
Oh, I can take it.
- 뭐든지 다 견딜 수 있어
- 다행이군
- I can take anything you dish out.
- Good.
이건 아무 것도 아냐
Because that was nothing.
덱스, 나와라
내 말 들리나?
Dex, come in. Do you read me?
덱스, 내 말 들리나?
Do you read me, Dex? Copy.
덱스!
Dex!
Dex.
사방에 깔렸군
They're everywhere.
조심해! 조!
Joe, look out!
덱스!
Dex!
토튼코프가
왜 이런 짓을 했을까?
Why would Totenkopf do this?
덱스를 왜?
이해가 안돼
Why Dex?
It doesn't make any sense.
뭔가를 찾고 있었던거야
He was looking for something.
덱스는 신호가 어디서
송출되는지 안다고 했어
Dex said he knew where
the transmission was coming from.
뭔가를 알아낸게
틀림없어
He must have got too close.
- 내게 뭔가를 알려주려...
- 조
- He was trying to tell me something...
- Joe.
역시 덱스야
Good boy, Dex.
네팔
바가스 박사가 쓴 일지야
These journals belong to Dr. Vargas.
실종되기 전 제닝스 박사에게
건네준게 틀림없어
He must have passed them on to
Dr. Jennings before his disappearance.
- 세상에
- 왜?
- My God.
- What?
토튼코프 박사는 12살 때
첫 특허권을 따냈대
"Totenkopf was awarded his first
patent when he was 12 years old.
17살에는 박사 학위를
2개나 받았으며
By 17, he had already received
two doctorates
당대 최고의
두뇌로 인정받았어
and was one of the most highly
regarded minds of his day.
그가 사라지고 1년 후
온갖 소문이 돌기 시작했어
One year after his disappearance,
ominous rumors began circulating.
토튼코프가 뭔가를
시작 했다고 말이지
Whispers that Totenkopf
had begun work
"종말의 기계"라고 알려진
뭔가를 연구하고 있다고 말야
on what was darkly hinted
to be a doomsday device.
그를 찾으려는
모든 노력은 실패했고
Efforts to locate him
have consistently failed,
현재까지 그의 행방은
의문으로 남아있어
and to this day, his whereabouts
remain a mystery.
그의 동료에 대해서는
더욱 알려진게 없어
Even less is known
about his companion,
이 기계들을 조종하는
배후자가 틀림없어
an assassin who controls
his machines."
바로 이 여자가
덱스를 데려간거야
She's the one who took Dex.
또 뭐가 있지?
What else?
유닛 11을 위한
물자 공급 기록이군
These are Unit 11 supply logs.
지난 3년간 이 기계들을
이용해 수집한
This is everything he's used
his machines to collect
모든 것에 대한 기록이야
도시의 발전기를 포함해서
for the last three years,
including generators from the city.
무슨 전세계적인
쇼핑 리스트 같애
It reads like a shopping list
from all over the world.
박사가 무슨 일을
한걸까?
What have you been up to, doctor?
괜찮을거야, 조
덱스는 알아서 잘 할거야
It'll be all right, Joe.
Dex can look after himself.
꼭 찾을 수 있을거야
We'll find him.
내 오랜친구, 조
My old friend Joe.
- 조, 다시 만나서 반가워
- 그동안 잘지냈어, 카지
- So glad to see you again.
- It's good to see you too, Kaji.
여긴 폴리 퍼킨스
함께 갈거야
This is Polly Perkins.
She'll be coming with us.
반갑습니다
Nice to meet you.
- 카지, 필요한 지도는 구했어?
- 그래, 안에 있어
- Kaji, did you get the maps I needed?
- Yeah, they're inside.
내가 말한것도 가져왔지?
Did you get a little something
for me?
물론이지
부탁한대로 세 박스야
Of course. Three cases,
just like you asked.
비에나 소시지! 아, 정말
오랫동안 못 먹어봤어
Vienna sausages.
My God, it's been so long.
카지, 티베트어 좀
할 줄 알아?
Kaji, how's your Tibetan?
"추으면 젖꼭지가 땡땡해져"
따라 와, 지도 보여줄게
Come, I'll show you the maps.
- 잘 아는 사람이야?
- 코지?
- How well do you know him?
- Kaji?
그는 베테랑이야
정찰 임무를 맡았었는데, 왜?
He's old legion.
Reconnaissance. Why?
못 믿겠어
I don't trust him.
재밌군, 그도 널
못 믿겠다고 했는데
That's funny, he said
the same thing about you.
여기, 옷 갈아 입어
지금 옷은 두고 가
Here. Get changed.
Your clothes stay behind.
우리가 갈 곳에는
하이힐이 필요없어
You won't be needing high heels
where we're going.
덱스가 신호를 여기
카라칼의 북쪽 골짜기에서
Dex tracked the signal to here,
this valley north of Karakal.
나오는 걸로 추적했어
여기서 신호가 나온거야
This is where
the transmission originated.
왜 지명이 없지?
여기가 어디야?
Why is there no writing here?
What is this place?
- 샴발라
- 아는 곳이에요?
- Shambhala.
- You know it?
금지된 곳이죠
It is forbidden.
카라샤크라의 진원지로
알려졌죠, 티벳의 전설
It's said to be the source
of the Kalachakra, Tibetan magic.
그곳 사람들은 초인적인
힘이 있다고들 하지
Those who live there are said
to have supernatural powers.
거기까지 데려다
줄 수 있지? 카지?
You can get us there, Kaji,
can't you?
아무도 가보지 못한
곳이지, 매우 위험해
No one has ventured this far.
It's very dangerous.
샴발라는 카라샤크라 수도원
스님들의 보호를 받는다고 해
Shambhala is said to be protected by
the priests of the Kalachakra lamasery.
우릴 발견하면
죽일려고 할거야
If they find us there,
they will kill us.
왜? 여기가
왜 그렇게 특별한데?
Why? Why is this place so special?
샴바라는 여러 명칭으로 불리지
히브류인들은 "에덴"
Shambhala is known by many names.
To the Hebrew, it is Eden.
고대 그리스인들은
"엠포리오스"라고 했지
To the ancient Greek,
it was Empurios.
자넨 "샹글리라"로
알고 있을거야
You may know it as Shangri-la.
폭풍이 오고 있어, 아직도
가고 싶다면 지금 출발해야 돼
A storm is coming. If you still wish
to go, we must go now.
연락 좀 하고
I need to send a message.
패일리, 이게 제가 보내는
마지막 메시지일지 몰라요
Editor Paley, this may be the last
message you receive from me.
토튼코프 박사를
찾기 위해 이곳 네팔까지
We've tracked a radio signal to Nepal
in search of Dr. Totenkopf.
무선 신호를
추적해 따라왔습니다
사건은 점점 꼬이기만 하고
카운트다운에 대한
The story grows stranger
at every turn.
단서는 있지만 뭘
의미하는지 모르겠어요
Clues about a countdown.
But to what, I don't know.
시간이 없어요
I fear time is running out.
운이 좋으면 덱스와
기삿거리를 가지고 갈게요
With any luck, I'll be back soon
with Dex and the story.
행운을, 폴리 퍼킨스
I hope. Polly Perkins.
여기가 인류 문명이
끝나는 지점이야
This is where civilization stops.
지도에도 없는 곳이지
A blank on the map.
여기서부턴 조심해야 돼
We must be careful from here.
빨리!
Hurry.
저게 뭐지?
What is it?
채광촌 처럼 보이는데
It looks like a mining outpost.
여기서 뭔가 안 좋은
일이 있었나 봐
Something bad happened here.
폐쇄된 것 같은데
Seems to be abandoned.
저 사람들한테 우리가
내려갈거라고 말해
Tell your men we're heading down.
더 자세히
살펴봐야겠어
I want a closer look.
왜 그래, 조?
What is it, Joe?
우라늄이야
Uranium.
광산 전체가 오염됐어
The whole mine's contaminated.
- 여기 있으면 안돼
- 그럼 나가자
- We can't stay here.
- Let's go.
폴리는 어딨지?
Where's Polly?
폴리!
Polly!
퍼킨스양!
Miss Perkins?
떨어져서 찾아보자
We'll have to split up.
폴리!
Polly!
그녀를 놔 줘
Let her go.
튜브를 주면
여자를 살려주겠다
Give me the vials
and the girl will live.
튜브라니?
그게 무슨 소리야?
What vials?
What are you talking about?
두 번 묻지 않겠다
I will not ask a second time.
총 내려 놔!
Drop the gun.
무슨 말인지 모른다고
했잖아, 그냥 우릴 죽여
I told you, I don't know what you're
talking about. You'll just have to kill us.
원하는데로 해주지
As you wish.
잠깐, 잠깐만...
Wait! Wait. Wait.
미안하네, 조
I'm sorry, Joe.
잘있게나, 친구들
여행은 여기서 끝내게
Goodbye, my friends.
Your journey ends here.
말 할려고 했어, 조
내 말 믿어줘
I was going to tell you, Joe.
You have to believe me.
- 그 튜브 안에 든게 뭐야?
- 나도 몰라
- What was in those vials?
- I don't know.
- 나보고 그걸 믿으라고?
- 진실을 말하는거야, 조
- You expect me to believe that?
- I'm telling the truth, Joe.
제닝스 박사가 죽기 전에
나한테 준거야
Dr. Jennings gave them to me
just before he died.
그게 만약 토튼코프 손에
들어가면 세계의 종말이 오고
He said that the world would end
and the countdown would begin
카운트다운이
시작할거라고 했어
if Totenkopf got his hands on them.
당신, 처음부터 나한테
거짓말만 했어
You've done nothing but lie to me
from the beginning.
맞아, 거짓말은 했지만
과장이 아냐
Okay, I'm a liar. But I don't exaggerate.
That is what he said.
그가 그렇게 말했다구
저게 바로 토튼코프가
찾던거군
That was what Totenkopf
was looking for.
- 그래서 덱스를 납치했군
- 미안해
- That's why he took Dex.
- I'm sorry.
난 정말 일이 이렇게
될 줄은 몰랐어
I never meant for any of this
to happen.
저 소리 들었어?
Do you hear that?
다이나마이트야
Dynamite.
또 그 소리가 들려
That noise again.
움직여!
Move!
뭐하는거야?
What are you doing?
이리 와!
Come on!
대단해
Oh, great.
이제 살았군
We're safe.
폴리, 이게
마지막일지도 몰라
Polly, this may be
our last moment together.
그래서 뭐 하나
물어볼게 있어
There's something
I need to ask you.
뭔데, 조?
Yes, Joe?
당신이 내 비행기의
연료관을 잘랐지?
Did you cut my fuel line?
젠장! 네 빌어먹을 비행기
망가뜨리지 않았어!
Damn it! I didn't sabotage
your lousy airplane!
마지막 순간까지 나한테
한다는 말이 고작 그거야?
Our last moments on earth
and this is all you have to say to me?
제발 더 이상 싸우지 않고
죽을 순 없어?
Could we just for once die
without all this bickering?
여기 있었네!
There you are.
- 문은 왜 잠궜어?
- 뛰어!
- Why did you lock the door?
- Run!
내 필름!
My film.
폴리, 놔 둬!
시간이 없어!
Polly, leave it!
There's no time!
폴리
Polly.